Guide to the William Everard Gardiner Transportation Collection M0326
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William Everard Gardiner transportation collection
1869-1940
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gardiner, William Everard
M0326
6 Linear Feet (8 boxes, 1 carton, 1 map folder)
Collection of photographs and research material concerning railroads, street cars and other public transportation in and around Oakland and Berkeley, California.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Photograph negatives are not available.
Scope and Contents
Collection of photographs and research material concerning railroads, street cars and other public transportation in and around Oakland and Berkeley, California from historian and local railway employee William Everard Gardiner (1869-1949). Born in Cedar County, Iowa, Gardiner worked for the San Francisco-Oakland Terminal Railways and later the Key System (which took over the SF-O Terminal Railways in 1924). He was Chief Instructor and Superintendent of Schedules through at least 1928.
Gardiner was an early member of the Pacific Railway Club (est. 1917) and Railway and Locomotive Historical Society (est. 1925). He was also a photographer, and the collection contains negatives and prints made by him, along with reproductions of older images. Some of the photographs by Gardiner document the 1906 earthquake’s effects in Berkeley. There is also information on the general history of Alameda County.
The collection contains photographs, manuscripts & typescripts on history (some transcribed), correspondence, newspaper & magazine clippings (primarily 1920s Oakland Tribune articles), ephemera including many examples of train tickets, scrapbooks, and other material. Gardiner material may be present in other Stanford transportation collections; likewise other material may have been added to the Gardiner collection in the past.
Hopkins Transportation Library.; Transportation -- History.; Railroads -- History; Oakland (Calif.) -- History.; Berkeley (Calif.) -- History.; Railfans; Gardiner, William Everard; Key System Transit Lines (Calif.); San Francisco-Oakland Terminal Railways; Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America
- Correspondence
  - D.L. Joslyn re: membership in Railway and Locomotive Historical Society (RLHS), January 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: streetcar pictures, February 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanley Keefe re: 19th Anniversary of Central Car House (addresses Gardiner as "Mr. Timetable Bill"), March 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: pictures of cars and locomotives including "Liberty", March 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: S.P. Bulletin, snow plows, State Capitol, streetcars, ferries, March-April 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: RLHS, May 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - William S. Wollner re: subscription to Northwestern Pacific Rail's Headlight monthly and the work of E.Holden, NPRR's Custodian of Records, May 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: Bulletin, photos, Keynote magazine, May 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - F.W. Martin re: RLHS, June 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: lists and photos, July 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: photos, January 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: photos, September 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: ferry, Cliff House, RR photos, etc., October 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: Bulletin contribution, Fair of the Iron Horse in Baltimore, September-November 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D.L. Joslyn re: San Francisco & San Jose engine builders, July 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wm. P. St. Sure, VP and General Manager to employees re: health benefits, May 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - East Bay Transit Co., Wm. P. St.Sure to Div. 818, Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America (Daniel Carlson, President) re: terms of collective bargaining agreement, October 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wm. P. St.Sure, V-P and General Manager to employees re: life insurance benefits, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Union Pacific Railroad form letter re: map of Pony Express route in early 1860s, September 10, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Notes
  - Notes taken from the San Francisco Directory 1860-61 re: Market Street, SF&SJ, Omnibus, and Folsom St. railroads, steamboat ferries (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on railroads from Halley's history of Alameda County (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on California railroads, especially SF&SJ and California&Nevada (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on East Bay transportation, 1853-1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on ferry service between SF, San Antonio and Oakland in the 1850s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on locomotives (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - List of locomotive photos (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - List of names and dates [conductors & motor men, inspections?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on establishment of Bay Area towns and cities (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on experimental run from Ogden to Oakland (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes re: hack fare in 1887 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes re: Mr. Frost's trip from SF to San Pablo by stage coach (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes re: Mr. Whipple's commencement of O,SL&H Electric Railway August 9, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes re: school bond issues, 1915, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes re: Bulletin 182, August 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes re: cities and systems (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bus & Jitney files
  - Bus, Motor Coach route maps etc., 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Jitney Bus History [Oakland, possibly by Gardiner] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Oakland Jitney Bus Ordinance No. 810 NS of May 18, 1915 as amended by No. 957 of Jan. 13, 1016 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vehicle Act, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blueprint map of downtown Oakland showing district where jitneys are not permitted (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Key System history
  - Chronological History of Early Horse, Steam and Cable Lines of the East Bay District, 1863-1890 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronological History of the Key System Transit Co. and Its Predecessors 1896-1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Chronological History of the "Key Route," 1903-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chronological History of the Bus Lines of the Key System Transit Co., 1921-1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Railroad files
  - Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe, GD Bradley (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Northern Pacific Railway Co. Structural Pre-Inventory Notes, Interstate Commerce Commission, Division of Valuation, April 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Northern Pacific Railway notes on locomotives (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Santa Clara Interurban RR vs. Board of Trustees of the Town of Mayfield (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Southern Pacific timetables Northern Division No. 40, 44, 46, 51, 56; Coast Division No. 2, 3, 4, 6, 11. Presented by H.F. Bassett, March 1928, 1882-1891 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Locomotive classification sheets: North West Pacific; Oregon & California; Oregonian; California Pacific; Southern Pacific; Northern Railway Co.; Central Pacific; Stockton & Copperopolis; South Pacific Coast Narrow Gauge; San Francisco & Oakland; San Francisco & Alameda (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Oakland, San Leandro & Haywards Electric Railway documents 1893 (photostats) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - set of index cards chronicling train accidents from approximately 1847-1915, filed alphabetically by railroad company (Box 5, Card-box 2)
- Streetcar files
  - Electric Railway Motors and Control System, Source Research Bureau (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Growth of Electric Railways, Frank J. Sprague, Source Research Bureau, October 1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - K Controllers, Source Research Bureau, April 1921 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Oakland Railroad Co. - History of Telegraph Ave. Line by "Bill" Gardiner (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Timetables of Oakland Railroad Co. Telegraph Ave. and San Pablo Ave. Lines, 1888-1901 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Oakland, San Leandro & Haywards Electric Railway Co. Run Sheets and Time Card, 1894 etc. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Oakland Transit Co. Transfer Slips 1901-1905 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - street railroads, Los Angeles 1929-1936 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Scope and Contents
    typescript stamped Hopkins Tranportation Library.
- Miscellaneous
  - Alameda Co. Rail timetable, newspaper clipping, May 23, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oakland Consolidated Street Railway employee ticket (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oakland Parking Ordinance, Oakland Tribune, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Railway and Locomotive Historical Society membership dues receipt, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Announcement of Acquisition of the San Fran.-Oak. Term. Rys. by the Key System Transit Co., January 15, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oakland Transit Company and Syndicate Railways mounted letterheads (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gardiner certificate, deputy sheriff of Alameda County, January 1919 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gardiner membership certificate, Amalgamated Assoc. of Street Railway Employees of America, Div. 192, July 1902 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gardiner membership withdrawal card, Amalgamated Assoc. of Street Railway Employees of America, Div. 192, September 1903 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Western Railroader for the Western Railfan, 1954, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bulletin No. 2289 by JP Potter, Supt. Transportation, re: new hourly rates for motormen, conductors, brakemen [carbon], April 1919 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oakland and San Francisco RR Ferry schedule (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - DeLuxe Transportation Co. schedule, San Jose-Oakland Service, July 1919 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pacific Gas & Electric general lighting service schedule, April 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oakland Charter Amendment, November 1916 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Argument in Favor of Oakland Charter Franchise Amendment (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Highway Transportation Re-Makes America booklet, National Highway Users Conference, September 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Duluth Aerial Ferry Bridge booklet, c. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Spring Wonder Trip Fifth Railroad Fan Excusion souvenir brochure, May 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Santa Fe System Lines "The Railroad" booklet, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Four Thousand Feet of Timetable," Bus Lines, August 1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Please Pass the Box Car," Colliers, August 13, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Motor Land article (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gardiner employee cards, SF-Oakland Terminal Railways, 1917-1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gardiner employee cards, Key System Transit Company, 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Key System Rifle Club membership cards, 1916-1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Key System Level Club membership card, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pacific Railway Club receipt,membership cards, 1918-1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Other membership cards and passes (including Oakland Chamber of Commerce, hunting and fishing licenses, Red Cross, etc.) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SF-O Terminal Railways Employe Exposition Trip Pass, November 11, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Imperial Railway Bureau, Tokyo calling card (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - First Fall Foto Festival, Western Pacific Railroad, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - insurance forms (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Santa Fe System Lines ad, Time, November 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photo reproductions of Lost Continent maps by theosophical publishing society, with notes on verso (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings
  Most are from the Oakland Tribune, but there are also clippings from the San Francisco Examiner, News, Chronicle and Bulletin.
  - Boulder Dam, 1931-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bridges, including Bay Bridge, Golden Gate, Carquinez, Martinez-Benecia, Antioch, 1916-1935 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Local and state history, especially Oakland and Berkeley, 1916-1926 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Key System, SF-O Terminal Railways news, including 1917 strikes and 1933 Key Pier fire, 1916-1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Oakland, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Oakland estuary, Webster Street Bridge, etc., 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Oakland harbor, industry, 1916-1927 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Oakland Traction Co. and other local railroads, 1915-1919 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Railroads, 1916-1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Transportation, including jitneys, Twin Peaks Tunnel, one-man safety cars, 1916-1931 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - War, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Misc., 1913-1930 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Unsorted, but related to above topics, 1916-1929 (Box 2, Folder 13, Box 3, Folders 1-3)
  - newspapers: San Francisco Examiner, Oakland Tribune, Oakland Post Enquirer, 1925-1927 (Map-folder 10)
- Tickets and passes
  - tickets, passes & conductor forms (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Southern Pacific; Alameda, Oakland & Piedmont; Oakland RR; Oakland Cable; Folsom St. Railroad; Ferries and Cliff House Railway; Oakland, San Leandro & Haywards Rail; Oakland Traction Company, etc. Includes press pass for High Street to Hayward bicycle race October 13, 1885
  - San Francisco-Oakland Terminal Railways/Key System employee passes (cancelled and samples), 1914-1926 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - scrapbook: Office of General Superintendent, Samples of Tickets and Instructions Regarding Honoring of Same, Over All Lines of San Francisco-Oakland Railways. For Stanley Keefe, c. 1914-1920. "Rec'd 1914" on front (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Captioned display of train tickets and tokens from Oakland Railroad Company, 14th St. Railroad, Oakland, Brooklyn & Fruitvale Railroad (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - San Francisco-Oakland Terminal Railways and Key tickets and passes (Box 5, Card-box 1)
  - Capitol Transit Company (Washington, D.C.) weekly passes, 1930s-1940s (Box 5, Card-box 1)
  - small scrapbook of passenger check tickets from the Midwest, circa 1917-1922 (Box 5, Card-box 2)
    mostly Pullman claim tickets. Annotated by owner, including typescript of memories as WWI soldier traveling in around US
  - small album of tickets from California Railway, Oakland Transit Company, Oakland, San Leandro & Hayward (Box 5, Card-box 2)
  - Key System PPIE tokens, 1915 (Box 5, Card-box 2)
    small paper key-shaped souvenirs, one with a ribbon
  - Richmond & San Rafael Ferry Company badge, 1915 (Box 5, Card-box 2)
- Scrapbooks
  Most have a SUL bookplate with inscription "In memory of William Everard Gardiner." There is some damage to the scrapbooks, including paint and warpage.
  - article transcriptions, Oakland Daily Transcript and Encinal of Alameda 1869-1871; Oakland Tribune articles 1892 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - History of Transportation in Oakland and East Bay District. article transcriptions from Oakland Tribune, Encinal of Alameda, Oakland Daily Transcript 1869-1899 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, mixed subjects, 1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook of W.E. Gardiner, Instructor S.F.O.T. Rys. August, 1916. SF-O Transit Railways Re-Organization 1916; Key Route 1916-1917; "Today 20 Years Ago" column 1916-1920; etc. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings. WE Gardiner, Schedule Supervisor, Started January 1922, 1918-1922 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: Bay Bridge, Golden Gate, Oakland Esurary Tubem Carquinez Bridge, 1927-1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings: Bay Bridge, Golden Gate, 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook with pages from Transit Journal, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook dating June 19, 1937, 1939, containing articles from Saturday Evening Post, Colliers, Liberty, Science, etc. concerning politics, astronomy, geology, labor, travel etc. Some hand copied articles and excerpts and typewritten copies of Research Bureau reports. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Photo Scrapbooks
  Some prints are reproductions or published real photograph postcards. However, several have an embossed stamp identifying Gardiner as photographer. There is also a substantial amount of textual material in the scrapbooks.
  - Berkeley, University of California (Box 7, Folder 1)
    transcribed excerpts from Janes' Ilustrated History of the University of California; Oakland Tribune article on Oakland's first school house, June 1921; Six photos (some missing): University of California, DeLuxe Coach, DeLuxe Station, Hayward, Clay St. Hill Railroad, San Francisco
  - California Missions (Box 7, Folder 2)
    California Missions (published photo postcards with captions); Oakland photos: church, City Hall Plaza, Hotel Alta, Old Webster St. Bridge approach; Other: Key Ferry "Fernwood," AT&SF Railroad, 1700 Series at Cajon Pass
  - Oakland (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Aerial views of city and harbor; photos of streets and buildings; Oakland streetcars. 46 photographs: Oakland Inner Harbor 1910; 12th St. Dam 1910; 14th & Clay c.1909-1910; Near City Hall, c. 1910; View over Bay to Marin; Oakland aerial views; Pr. Richmond, 1912; UC Berkeley, aerial view; Richmond? aerial view; Crews, Telegraph Ave. Barns; Leona Heights Car; Elmhurst Car Barn; Streetcars; Broadway and 11th, early 1880s; City Hall Plaza; Key System Building; Horse Car at SF Exhibition, 1915; City Hall from Washington St. postcard; Oakland Mole postcard; published photographs: Oakland City Hall, Old SP Depot, Road to Trestle Glen
  - Oakland, earthquake, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    16 photos showing effects of earthquake. Most buildings and streets identified in captions.
  - Oakland, streetcars (Box 7, Folder 5)
    81 photos (one dated 1904, some older copy prints). Streetcars of Alemeda Oakland & Piedmont Electric Railway, 14th St. RR, O & BRT Co., Oakland, Brooklyn & Fruitvale Railway, Oakland Con. St. Railway, Oakland Transit Co., Oakland, San Leandro & Haywards; Oakland harbor; Oakland streets and buildings; OTC Div. Supt. and Insprctor group portrait; Time schedules, A,O&P; Grading of Grand Ave. at Adam's Point; California Railways - steam; Unidentified locomototive; City of Richmond ferry; unidentified ferries; Oakland Traction Co. tower truck, 1907, tower wagon 1898; unidentified group in bleachers; unidentifed group with pompoms and megaphone.
    Scrapbook also contains SF-Oakland Terminal Railways Chart of Organization 1919, Rate Comparisons 1897-1917; Union contracts 1917, 1918, 1920; personnel records 1918-1920; passenger survey 1914; Tariffs 1921
    Blueprint of streetcar tracks, Broadway & San Pablo Ave.
    Golden Gate Ferry tariffs 1922
    Karfax 1920, 1921
    Newspaper clippings
  - Transportation: History of Transportation in California and East Bay (Box 7, Folder 6)
    23 photos: Key System ferries Hayward, San Lendro and Fernwood; Oakland RR trains; South Pacific Coast RR trains; South Pacific RR ticket office; Unidentified group at 14th & Webster near South Pacific Coast locomotive 1882; Unidentified locomotives; Broadway, 1854- photo of illustration.
    Excerpts and notes from History of Alameda County
    Letter from A.N. Towne to C. Rivers Wilson January 1895 re: California railroad history
    Chronological history of incorporation of California railroad companies 1853-1899
    California & Oregon RR Secretary to E.C. Wright, Treasurer of Pacific Improvement Co. re: value of old stocks November 1900
    Maps of Southern Pacific Lines
    Transcription from Southern Pacific Bulletin May 1920
    photos of Oakland Daily Transcript articles from 1869
    Newspaper clippings 1919-1924
    Southern Pacific Bulletin March 1920
- Photographs, Berkeley & Oakland
  Old but in some cases later prints originally stored with nitrate negatives (which are not available but may be the subject of future digitization). More detailed notes are written on envelopes. There are multiple prints in some cases. Note: prints are extremely brittle and in some cases have already broken.
  Some photographs present here were probably not taken or collected by Gardiner and were added to his collection later.
  - Berkeley
    - Bancroft & Telegraph, 1879 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 47th & Telegraph, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Broadway looking North from Moffitt & Blake Building, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Broadway & Webster, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 14th & Brush East, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 14th & Brush West, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 17th & Grove, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Tubbs Hotel, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Planting of Lincoln Tree, Lincoln Square, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Elmhurst Hotel, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - First MC Church, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Taken from wharf (fragment), 1918 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Alcatraz, Fort Scott and US Transport dock from hills above old Exposition grounds, SF, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - PG&E building, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Pairier Home, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Views of New Line, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Baseball team, Western & Central Districts, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - PG&E Substation, 51st & Shattuck, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Courthouse site at 12th & Fallon, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - New Park St. Bridge Opening, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 38th & Grove showing highway construction, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 38th & Market highway construction, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - View from hill to the north of E.14th at Hayward, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 9th & Broadway (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 11th & Broadway (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 12th St. Dam and culvert (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 49th & Telegraph. Dr. Prindle's Drug Store (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Berkeley Hills near 54th & Claremont from Carrosso's Observatory (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hinlon House, 3855 Telegraph Ave. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Piedmont Power Station (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Oakland
    - Sacred Heart Convent [published], 1868, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Broadway & San Pablo, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Broadway & Telegraph, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th & Broadway, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th & Webster from College Tower, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 13th & Broadway from College Tower, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 14th & Alice towards hills, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 14th & Broadway towards San Pablo, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 14th & Franklin, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 14th & Harrison towards hills, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th & Broadway, 1873 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th & Broadway, SE Corner, 1873 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - From City Hall Tower down Washington, 1878 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th & Franklin, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th St., Masonic Temple, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Allston from Shattuck, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - City Hall, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - First Presbyterian Church, 14th & Franklin, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - First M.E. Church, 14th & Clay, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 14th & Franklin from Masonic Temple, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Washington from 9th, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - From Carrosso's Observatory (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - From Masonic Temple (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 9th & Broadway, SE Corner (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - City Hall, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 12th St. Dam, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Marshall Jofreys on his visit to Oakland, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Oakland Town Hall, snow on hills, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Washington School on Shattuck, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Jefferson St. Extension from top of PG&E Building, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Pasey Tube construction, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 5620 Telegraph (no negative, one print stamped Gardiner, photographer), 1932 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Old Alameda Co. Courthouse and Jail at E.14th & 19th Ave., 1934 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - New Alameda Co. Courthouse, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bank of Savings, 12th & Broadway (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Broadway & Webster (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - City Hall Square [published] (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Oakland Guard (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - PG&E Station, 51st & Shattuck (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Rose Bowl (no negative) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - City Hall (Box 8, Folder 2)